Cameron Bisca

917-359-5270 | Brooklyn, NY | cjbisca@gmail.com Github | LinkedIn

FRONT END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Expressive developer with a background in service and performing arts. Hard technical skills in JavaScript, React and web design leveraged with creativity, high standards and a sharp focus for the customer experience. Uses collaboration and active listening to contribute to the synergy and productivity of the team. Enjoys the art of delivering to clients and target audiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React | React Native | HTML | CSS | Ruby on Rails | Git | Postgresgl | mySQL| Semantic

Web Developer: 1+ years experience with JavaScript(ES6), HTML, CSS & Semantic.

Infrastructure & Software Engineer: 1+ years experience with advanced web application stacks using technologies like React with Hooks and React Native for mobile; Ruby on Rails server side.

API & Data: RESTful API architecture and Postgresql/mySQL relational databases, using best practice developer tools and libraries like React Router, authentication and security with BCrypt and JWT, cloud storage with Active Storage.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

I Got Next - Frontend | Backend | Demo

Provides real time activity for basketball courts so users can find a court that fits their needs on a given day.

- Optimized forms and button behavior with reusable React components, hooks, and state.
- Developed a map querying Leaflets API so users can find courts via a responsive map.
- Formatted and styled using CSS flexbox and Semantic to build a simple and sleek interface.

Discourse - Github | Netlify

Users who are at odds regarding polarizing topics can connect based on common interests with the hope that these connections will establish a common ground between "enemies" and lead to meaningful discourse.

- Improved performance with controlled forms, state, reusable components, and hooks with the React framework.
- Implemented action cable chat feature using GetStream API offering expressive messaging and edit/delete capabilities.
- Created custom client side routing for easy navigation and action specific RESTful API requests.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Developer

04/2021

Flatiron "Nurturing Differences" Hackathon

New York, NY

- Collaborated with 4 developers to build "Discourse", a chatting app that connects users with social and political differences based on common interests to encourage meaningful discourse.
- Employed agile methodology and troubleshooting tactics to program under a tight deadline.
- Recognized by GetStream in "15 Stream Maker Account Projects We Love".

BartenderThe Finch, The Tasting Kitchen

10/2014 - 03/2020

ne Finch, The Tasting Kitchen

Brooklyn, NY / Los Angeles, CA
Increased sales by 8% through crafting seasonal cocktails informed by locally farmed products, and upselling premium spirits.

- Collaborated with wine makers, brewers, distillers, and chefs to produce exclusive tasting events.
- Reduced spending by 4% by managing inventory and tracking sales/trends.
- Organized and led staff training sessions to elevate the team's knowledge regarding higher end spirits.

Element Music Sound associate

New York, NY 06/2011 - 09/2014

Slashed spending by 5% by negotiating sound equipment contracts with music rental vendors.

- Assembled technical teams and kept all events within budget.
- Crafted stage plots, built call sheets and organized equipment specifications for events.
- Coordinated on behalf of Element music with event producers and third party vendors such as florists, photographers/videographers, catering, lighting designers, and miscellaneous entertainers to reach a common goal.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Certified Software Engineer

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, 15 week fully immersive hands-on coding bootcamp

11/ 2020 - 04/2021

Long Island University

Brookville, NY

Course work in Performing Arts and Communications

2011-2013